Guide to the Duke University Press Reference Collection, 1922-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University Press Reference collection 1922-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
1.5 linear feet Extent: 1050 Items
UA.01.11.0034
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Duke University Press Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Historical Note
The origins of the Duke University Press date back to 1892 and the establishment of the Trinity College Historical Society; in 1921 the Trinity College Press was officially founded. William T. Laprade served as the first Director until 1926. That same year, the Duke University Press was founded with William K. Boyd as Director.
Duke Press publishes both scholarly books and journals, primarily in the humanities and the social sciences. In the Press's early years, preference was given to works published by faculty, graduate students, and alumni; and to works focused on the "region south of the Potomac." As the University has grown and diversified, so has the Press; now it is best known for its publications in the broad and interdisciplinary area of theory and history of cultural production. By 1949 the press published 3-5 journals and 5-15 books per year. Currently (2008), Duke University Press publishes approximately 120 books annually and more than 30 journals. This places the Press's books publishing program among the twenty largest at American university presses, and the journals publishing program among the five largest.
Collection Overview
The Duke University Press Reference Collection contains clippings, reports, forms, correspondence, brochures, and catalogs that pertain to the history and operation of the Duke University Press. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. The materials in the collection date from 1922-ongoing.
Subject Headings
Duke University Press; Periodicals; Scholarly periodicals
Related Material
Bernard I. Duffey papers, 1957-1983.
University Archives. Duke University.
Duke University Press records, 1926-1991.
University Archives. Duke University.
South Atlantic Quarterly records, 1926-1986.
University Archives. Duke University.
William Thomas Laprade Papers, 1660-1975 (bulk 1898-1975).
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 3 Boxes
  - Announcements (Box 1)
  - History by Ashbel Brice, 1951
  - Brochures
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1950 (incomplete)
  - Clippings
  - Forms, correspondence, etc.
  - Books in Print, 1996-
  - Journals
  - National Collegiate Software Clearing House, 1989
  - Duke University (Trinity College) Press - Historical
  - Style Sheet
  - Trade Lists, 1922-1960
  - South Atlantic Quarterly, 1963-2002
  - Duke Mathematical Journal, undated
  - American Literature, editors, history, 1929-Ongoing
  - A93-54 (Box 2)
    - Reference, History, bulk 1981-1991
    - Reference, History, 1974-1992
    - Reference, History, 1982-1990
  - Report - June 30, 1928
  - Catalogues, 1990-2002 (Box 3)